Hello everyone
I am Canghai Jiusu
Another Spring Festival holiday has arrived
Just like last year,
I will continue to share some efficiency tools with everyone
This sharing will also be divided into two parts
First, I will select some frequently used tools from last year
introduce them in two separate videos
especially to introduce to everyone
their most significant feature evolutions from last year
Then, I will also make a few more videos for everyone.
introduce some new friends
And then
These are also tools that I've been using frequently in my daily routine recently
frequently used tools
hope that through the introduction of these tools
can equally help everyone
to enhance your daily work and study efficiency
Today, the tool we’re introducing to everyone
is the first tool in our entire productivity tools series
the app launcher tool Recast
So why do we start with this tool first?
also because this tool last year
has actually undergone significant capability enhancements
On one hand, it has started supporting Windows
This is a long-awaited capability that everyone has been looking forward to.
At the same time, it also supports iOS.
There are also some additional features like Recast
iterations of auxiliary features such as notes
So it's not just a traditional app launcher tool
It has now actually expanded into a wide range of capabilities
a versatile and integrated tool
More importantly
Last year, it deeply embraced AI.
AI that works
You will see a separate Recast AI page
On this page,
You can see that it has different forms of integration with AI
including something similar to this kind of
a form of ChatGPT dialogue
It's called AI chat
There are also some self-developed models.
and everyone can use it
including its integration with many existing models
Then everyone can use it as an XJPD-like
desktop and online tool to use
What's more important is that it also has a quick AI capability
This is what I use the most
and one of my most frequently used and favorite features
It fully leverages its nature as an app launcher
which means it can be used at any time
during the use of any other application
You can summon its dialog window
Just like this
Then within this window
You can input all kinds of questions
Then you can simply press the Tab key to execute an 'ask AI'
this capability operation
This is much more convenient than having to specifically open a ChatGPT window
or web page
and then engaging in a conversation is much more convenient
And then combined with
It now indeed integrates many different models
It can also be similar to the original trig p t
its desktop application
integrates AI capabilities from local applications
so it actually now has quite a lot to offer in terms of AI capabilities output
actually accomplishes quite a lot
Your automation assistant
When it comes to using it,
It can indeed be used on your desktop.
and there are many automated operations
maybe uh
But today, the main focus is to introduce the core feature
it's this Quick AI feature of his
Because this part is really great
very convenient to use
Then everyone just needs to follow the configuration methods demonstrated later
can be quickly put to use
Well, as for other capabilities,
You can explore more about it later
and many features are quite similar to CHEEPT or cloud desktop
Then I won't elaborate further here
Next, we'll show you how to enable it
and integrate third-party services into the Recast AI capabilities
So if you already have
especially many domestic model providers
You can use the following method
and quickly connect
and use the Quick AI capability anytime, anywhere
to help you improve your daily work efficiency
Well, the way to activate it is actually quite simple.
After invoking Recast
then everyone just needs to search for AI
Then find this recast setting
this item
Then expand this configuration interface
we will be directly navigated to this AI configuration section here
Here,
We need to scroll the settings list on the right to the bottom
Then, first enable a very important feature
called custom providers
which means custom model providers
This is turned off by default.
By default, it provides us with what you need to provide, ah
OpenAI and Anthropic or Google
or the keys for these four platforms: OpenRouter
Then, if you already have these keys ready
You can directly make a configuration here
then enter the key
you can directly use its additional
integration of custom API services
we all know the things mentioned earlier
It's not easy for us to obtain their keys.
stable and usable key
So the more recommended options are two ways
One option is if everyone's local configuration is decent
You can directly consider using Ollama
as a local model
to integrate into this recast AI for use
This is also a pretty good approach.
If your local configuration is not ideal
For You to use the online service instead
Using online services would be a bit more troublesome.
After first enabling the custom provider,
Then, everyone needs to come to this section
Then, this section is specifically for configuring
the location of a custom provider
Here you click on the review below
providers configure
After clicking this
You will come to a window
This window will
display the existing supplier templates you currently have
By default, there will only be this uh
the YAML file for the supplier template
Then in this file
You can see some default template configurations
Then what you need to do is
you create a new compressed file for your own providers
and then fill in all your provider configurations
Then you can get what we can use and access in recast AI
use and integrate custom third-party providers
So it's still quite troublesome.
It is not implemented as an interface-based approach
it requires everyone to manually write some content
That's why we need to specifically explain this matter
Let's take a look at the content of this template.
Well, this template isn't actually that complicated.
However, you need to write it according to its rules.
It is roughly divided into several parts
First, it's an array of providers
Then, you need to give it an ID
then give it a name
give it a base url
This is very important
because our third-party
Basically, we all need to have our own API
an access endpoint
then you can provide some keys
These keys can be bound to the corresponding models
Because different models may use different keys
So it has such a design
Then, uh, follow the writing style here
You can have some additional parameters
These are optional, uh
The most crucial part is that you also need to fill in the models here
then provide its id
and a description of its basic capabilities
what key to use
What is the approximate size of its context window?
Then which providers does it use
the method of access
You also need to match the provider here
corresponds to the key above
It looks quite complicated
Although he has actually provided you with a lot of annotations here
So if you find it troublesome here
don't know how to write
The best way is to throw it to something like clock code
or throw it to Cursor
Then let them help you based on the template file
help you write based on this example
Then you just give the vs to these agents
then input your key
then let them do the same
just set up a placeholder
Then you can fill it in yourself.
Let me show you a concrete example
For example, here I am using
our silicon flo interface
So here, our configuration is actually set up like this.
an array of providers
we just provide one item
Then its ID is slion cloud
Then, the most important parts are a few places
One is the base URL
You need to fill it in correctly
Fill in this, uh, globally accessible address
Then for the key, you can provide one here
the key corresponding to this platform
By default, it follows the OpenAI format.
So the name of my key is OpenAI
If you don't have these models below
If you don't need to bind additional keys
You just need to write it in a similar way below.
The most critical part in the model is the id
The ID must match the model name ID provided by the platform you are using.
The model name ID it provides must exactly match
After completing these configurations
Then you come to the RECASETTINGAI we saw earlier
you can find it in the custom providers
find custom providers
for example here
Actually, Me providers file has configured a light l
1M with a slicking float
After locating this provider
it means your initial configuration is successful
Next,
you can then go back to the top of this page
You can find the Quick AI model
Then here you can list
you can see all the models that you currently support
or some pre-configured models that he has already set up for you
Many are presets that are already fully available.
And then, well, some are, uh,
many require you to upgrade to the
can only be used in the recast pro package
but we won't dwell on that here
What's more crucial here is that we need to utilize
these additional custom models we have defined
It will have one on the far right
a box-like identifier
And here you can also see
You can select these models
and then proceed with your subsequent usage
For example, we have selected the configuration
and selected this GN5
This is also the latest open-source model from China, okay
After selecting it
You can't actually test it directly here
So let's make sure it's selected first
Then we'll go back to our, uh,
bring up our plant Recast window
Then we can randomly input something in here
Then we press the tab key
it can then proceed to ask the AI
So after asking AI, you can have follow-up questions
for example, what's your
I do the base model
All of these are possible
Now with this feature
Then if you have some questions to ask
AI and then you can perform an operation through this method
It's incredibly fast.
Then if you feel this operation is not sufficient enough
Then you can uh
Because this window will disappear once you close it
So you can continue using the command+j method
open a dedicated chat window
This is the aforementioned AI chat
specifically that dedicated chat box window
Here you have more operational Space.
For example, you can configure its tools here
It also has various extensions
you can use it
including these extensions
It can even include the ability to operate your local applications
including online capabilities
MCP
Actually, all of these can be operated here
So after entering this window,
It persists data
and you have more Space for operations
including actions like rolling back
then go to Drawing
open the center to initiate another branch for conversation
All operations can be performed here
So use Quick AI for a quick expansion
Then switch to
a more formal chat dialog box
a chat interface
Note that this is an additional conversation interface
This is not the interface we invoked earlier
So in your daily usage,
especially now that you've integrated third-party services
You will be very adept at performing such operations.
This is a very important capability.
At the same time, what is another particularly important capability we have?
It's in this extension here
You can create your own AI commands.
For example, we can select the command here and then
We can add a new command
For example, we can select 'create i command' here
Then, uh, you can just give it any name
For example, let's call it translate
Then you can tell it here how to translate
Then you select a bracket
after starting with the curly brace
Can you see it here?
It allows you to select different data sources
including four types of selected text
clipboard text, some parameters, and
selected browser
You can install the Recast extension in your browser
its own browser extension has the capability to
including the ability to select browser page operations
So with these capabilities in place
You can quickly create a command
and then perform an AI-based processing on the content you've selected
or quickly process the content you've already copied with AI capabilities
This feature is also very useful
for example, let's say 'translate selection into chinese'
Let's say this is the case
Then, for the model, we select GM5.
Then you can just leave it like that for now
Then you save it
Now you have a new feature
called translate
See?
This has already been injected into your entire Recast
create an AI command
Then we can also try to use it.
Let's go back here
Then we select one of its conversations
After selecting it
Then you bring up your Recast again
Note that you don't need to enter additional commands here
you can directly select this
the AI command you previously set up
Then it will proceed according to our previous settings
process the selected text through our prompt
and then process it
For example, after it processes the text
you can similarly obtain such a result
That means
in many of your current applications
or in web pages
if you want to add some uh
your custom processing
You can all do it through the method we saw earlier
You directly in
You can directly in its AI settings
Create a new AI command
Create a new ECOMMAND
You can enter any prompt
Then, attach the text you have selected from the clipboard
or the content of your browser's tab page
You can quickly build your own
custom AI processing capability
and this capability is something you can access right on the page
actually within your desktop platform
summon for use at any time
This is really imaginative
or offers a highly customizable operational Space
So this is also a feature I use quite frequently in my daily routine.
So, taking this opportunity to reintroduce Recast to everyone,
this opportunity
Let me give you an introduction
We hope everyone can make use of this feature
and then, uh, make use of its AI capabilities
Let's utilize this technique of using AI capabilities anytime, anywhere.
I believe it will greatly enhance everyone's daily work efficiency
will also be very helpful
Okay, that's all for today's share
Okay, thank you everyone